Michael Cornwell

Leader, Software Engineer, Prototyper

83188 Press Sharp Rd, Bush, LA 70431 Cell: (985) 710-6879 michael.a.cornwell@gmail.com

Formal Education

B.S. Major: Sociology Minor: Geology May 2010 Virginia Tech Blacksburg, VA

Programming Proficiencies

Python C# .Net JavaScript / CoffeeScript CSS

Database Experience

SQLite PostgreSQL MySQL MongoDB

Technologies / Skills

Django / Flask

Bootstrap
Git & SVN
Unit Testing &
TDD/BDD
Linux
Prototyping
REST
AWS

Hobbies

Docker

Microcontrollers & Prototyping Home Automation Homesteading Animal Husbandry Farming

Summary

Highly motivated individual who goes above and beyond. Experienced in providing fullstack solutions on both Linux and Windows systems. Requires no over sight, after having spent 5 years doing remote work. Able to handle and thrive in fast paced environments and spends personal time learning, growing and testing new software solutions, and building Internet of Things automation. Mike is interested in doing his part to build a better world.

Recent Experience

Full Stack Software Engineer, Dixie Fruits

www.dixiefruits.com

October 2016 to Present

Created multiple unique web enabled applications from concept to execution using *Python*, *Django*, *Linux*, *REST*, *AWS and JavaScript*.

- Created small local hightech enabled fruit tree nursery.
- Built and launched a mobile geo-enabled data collection and aggregation application.
- Setup, improved and maintained the Dixie Fruits ecommerce website.

Digital Forensic Software Engineer, KLC Networks

Tysons Corner, VA (Remote)

October 2011 to October 2016

Developed software for conducting digital forensic exploitation. *Python, IronPython, C#, Javascript, kml, linux, windows, computer-forensics*.

- Created forward thinking Processing, Reporting and UI rapid development Frameworks for forensic information unlike any that existed, or currently exists in 1 year without assistance.
- Created a rapid development geo-positional 3D visualization application using Google
 Earth that started out as an in-house prototype and ended up having the director of the
 National Media Exploitation Center requesting a formalized tool, in two weeks.
- Started as the junior member and quickly became the most indispensable person on the team, leading to being the only member allowed to telecommute.

Mid-Level Intel Analyst, Foreign Terrorist Tracking Task Force (FBI)

Crystal City, VA

June 2010 to October 2011

Conducted intelligence analysis using link analysis tools. Python, excel

- Created an automated message data handling and parsing process that has allowed analysts to process messages 20x-1000x faster. Process is still in use today.
- Provided recommendations and debug support for developers of the automated message handling system and telephonic link-analysis programs.

Senior Economic Political Intelligence Analyst, USMC

Helmand Province, Afghanistan

April 2009 to November 2009

Performed political liaison and intelligence work for 2nd Marine Expeditionary Brigade for senior Afghan, British, and American political offices, as a Corporal (normally a position conducted by mid to senior grade commissioned officers).

- Commonly referred to as a major "powerbroker" in Helmand by Marine Corps staff
 officers and Afghan government officials due to superior influence in assisting change and
 decision making.
- Awarded Navy and Marine Corps Commendation Medal for exhibiting exceptional meritorious service performing work responsibilities at a significantly higher than level of responsibility.